A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.1, Series 300 Latin America - Series 833 Lebanon FA386b
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Germany, 1920-1970; 717; 8.8 Cubic Feet; 22 __Boxes __8.8 cubic feet
  - PWS MANN A, A-1 Postwar Survey - Mann, Albert R. "Educational Conditions in Postwar Germany" Printed Supplementary Material (qq-zz), (aaa-kkk), 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - PWS MANN A, A-1 Postwar Survey - Mann, Albert R. "Educational Conditions in Postwar Germany" Printed Supplementary Material (qq-zz), (aaa-kkk), 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - PWS MANN A, A-1 Postwar Survey - Mann, Albert R. "Educational Conditions in Postwar Germany" Printed Supplementary Material (qq-zz), (aaa-kkk), 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - PWS MANN B Postwar Survey - Mann, Albert R. "Educational Conditions in Postwar Germany" Handwritten Notes, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - PWS MANN B Postwar Survey - Mann, Albert R. "Educational Conditions in Postwar Germany" Handwritten Notes, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - PWS MANN B-1 Postwar Survey - Mann, Albert R. "Educational Conditions in Postwar Germany" Typescript of Handwritten Notes (2 copies), 1947 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Program and Policy, 1931, 1933-1938, 1945-1953 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Program and Policy, 1931, 1933-1938, 1945-1953 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Program and Policy, 1931, 1933-1938, 1945-1953 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Program and Policy - Reports, 1950-1951; 3 Items (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Rolfes, Max - (Agriculture), 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - SCH-1 Schorske, Carl E. "Diary of Trip to Germany", 1950 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - University of Cologne - Von Wiese, Leopold V. - (Sociology), 1947-1950 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - University of Kiel - Schneider, Eric - (Economics), 1946, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Youth Program - (Coursework, Great Britain), 1948-1950 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Germany - Medical Sciences, 717.A
    - Dresden City Hospital - (Schob, Franz, Herediatary Degenerative Diseases), 1932 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Emergency Aid, 1922-March 1924 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Emergency Aid, 1922-March 1924 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Emergency Aid, 1922-March 1924 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Emergency Aid, 1922-March 1924 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Emergency Aid, 1922-March 1924 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Emergency Aid, April 1924-1926 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Emergency Aid, April 1924-1926 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Frankfurt University - Anatomy - (Bluntschli, H.), 1931 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Forschungsanstalt Fur Psychiatrie, Munich - Historical Record - FORS, 1925-1928 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Forschungsanstalt Fur Psychiatrie, Munich - Research, 1930-1934 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Forschungsanstalt Fur Psychiatrie, Munich - Research, 1930-1934 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Forschungsanstalt Fur Psychiatrie, Munich - Research, 1935-1940, 1945-1948, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Forschungsanstalt Fur Psychiatrie, Munich - Research, 1935-1940, 1945-1948, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Forschungsanstalt Fur Psychiatrie, Munich - Research, 1935-1940, 1945-1948, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Forschungsanstalt Fur Psychiatrie, Munich - Research, 1928-1939; 12 Items (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Frankfurt University - Medical School, 1931, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Heckscher Institute, Munich - (Isserlin, Max, Psychopathology), 1933-1935, 1938-1941 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm Institute, Berlin - Anthropology - (Fischer, Eugen), 1932-1935 (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm Institute, Berlin - Brain Research, 1928-1939 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm Institute, Halle - Physiological Chemistry - (Abderhalden, Emil), 1931-1935 (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Medical Literature, 1920-1922 (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Medical Literature, 1923-1926 (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - Reichsgesundheitsamt, Berlin - Gildermeister, E. - (Virus Diseases), 1928, 1932, 1934-1935 (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Robert Koch Institute, Berlin, 1928, 1931-1936 (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - Uhlenhuth, Edward, 1922-1924 (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - UH-1 Uhlenhuth, Edward "Medical Education in Germany", 1922 (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - University of Berlin - Gynecology - (Zondek, Bernard), 1931-1933 (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - University of Berlin - Medical Clinic - (Jaensch, Walter; Seelig, Fritz), 1930-1933, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - University of Berlin - Pathology - (Rossle, Robert), 1933 (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - University of Bonn - Pathology - (Schultz-Brauns, Otto), 1930-1933 (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - University of Breslau - Neurological Laboratory - (Foerster, Ottfried), 1930-1937, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - University of Breslau - Pharmacology and Experimental Therapy, 1931-1932, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - University of Breslau - Physiology - (Winterstein, Hans), 1933-1936 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - University of Breslau - Psychiatry and Neurology - (Lange, Johannes; Wagner, Werner), 1933-1941 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - University of Breslau - Psychiatry and Neurology - (Wagner, Werner), 1949 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - University of Dusseldorf - Medical Clinic - (Dahmann, H.), 1930 (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - University of Freiburg - Hygiene - (Uhlenhuth, Paul), 1930-1931 (Box 12, Folder 82)
    - University of Freiburg - Medical Clinic - (Thannhauser, S. J.), 1932-1934 (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - University of Freiburg - Neuropsychiatric Clinic - (Beringer, Kurt), 1936-1940, 1946, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - University of Freiburg - Neuropsychiatric Clinic - (Beringer, Kurt), 1936-1940, 1946, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - University of Freiburg - Pathological Anatomy - (Aschoff, Ludwig), 1930-1935 (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - University of Giessen - Pathology - (Schopper, Werner), 1933 (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - University of Gottingen - Physiology - (Rein, Hermann), 1932-1937, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 88)
    - University of Gottingen - Physiology - (Rein, Hermann), 1932-1937, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - University of Greifswald - Pharmacology - (Holtz, Peter), 1932 (Box 12, Folder 90)
    - University of Halle - Physiology - (Abderhalden, Emil), 1931-1932 (Box 12, Folder 91)
    - University of Hamburg - Neurology - (Schaltenbrand, Georg), 1932-1935 (Box 12, Folder 92)
    - University of Kiel - Schroeder, Robert - (Obstetrics and Gynecology), 1930 (Box 12, Folder 93)
    - University of Konigsberg - Dermatology - (Dorffel, Julius), 1933 (Box 12, Folder 94)
    - University of Konigsberg - Surgery - (Biebl, Max), 1930 (Box 12, Folder 95)
    - University of Leipzig - Physiological Chemistry - (Thomas, Karl), 1929-1939, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 96)
    - University of Munich - Animal Pathology, 1932-1933, 1936-1937 (Box 12, Folder 97)
    - University of Munich - Psychiatric Clinic, 1932-1936, 1938-1940 (Box 12, Folder 98)
    - University of Wurzburg - Medical Clinic - (Strieck, Fritz), 1929-1930 (Box 12, Folder 99)
    - University of Wurzburg - Neurology - (Schaltenbrand, Georg; Tonnis, W.), 1935-1937 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - University of Wurzburg - Neurology - (Schaltenbrand, Georg; Amador, Luis), 1950-1951, 1952-1955 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - University of Wurzburg - Neurology - (Schaltenbrand, Georg; Amador, Luis), 1950-1951, 1952-1955 (Box 12, Folder 102)
    - University of Wurzburg - Pathology - (Letterer, Erich), 1931, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - University of Wurzburg - Physiology - (Schriever, Hans), 1934-1936 (Box 12, Folder 104)
    - Virchow Krankenhaus,: Berlin - (Friedemmann, Ulrich; Infectious Diseases), 1932 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - Germany - Nursing, 717.C
    - (Nursing), 1927-1928 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - Germany - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 717.D
    - Hannover Technical High School - Chemistry - (Biltz, W.), 1931-1934 (Box 12, Folder 107)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm Institute, Berlin-Dahlem - Biochemistry - (Neuberg, C.), 1932-1936 (Box 13, Folder 108)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm Institute, Berlin-Dahlem - Biology, 1931-1937 (Box 13, Folder 109)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm Institute, Berlin-Dahlem - Physical and Electrical Chemistry, 1929-1935, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 110)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm Institute, Plon - Hydro-Biology - (Thienemann, August), 1931-1933 (Box 13, Folder 111)
    - Karlsruhe Technical High School - Physical Chemistry - (Kuhn, W.; Equipment), 1931 (Box 13, Folder 112)
    - Ladenburg, Rudolf - (Physics), 1930-1931 (Box 13, Folder 113)
    - Max Planck Institute For Medical Research, Gottingen - Biochemistry - (Thomas, Karl), 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 114)
    - Munich Technische Hochschule - Chemistry - (Fischer, Hans), 1930-1939, 1945-1947 (Box 13, Folder 115)
    - Munich Technische Hochschule - Chemistry - (Fischer, Hans), 1930-1939, 1945-1947 (Box 13, Folder 116)
    - Oldenberg, Otto - (Physics), 1929 (Box 13, Folder 117)
    - Schratz, Eduard - (Plant Ecology, Equipment), 1930 (Box 13, Folder 118)
    - University of Freiburg - Physical Chemistry (Von Hevesy, Georg), 1930-1934 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    - University of Freiburg - Zoology - (Spemann, Hans), 1931 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    - University of Gottingen - Inorganic Chemistry, 1931-1935, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 121)
    - University of Gottingen - Physics (Franck, J.; Equipment), 1931-1932 (Box 13, Folder 122)
    - University of Gottingen - Zoology - (Kuhn, Alfre), 1934-1937 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - University of Hamburg - Physical Chemistry - (Stern, Otto; Equipment and Supplies), 1932-1933 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - University of Heidelberg - Chemical Institute (Freudenberg, Karl), 1930-1932, 1936-1937, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - University of Heidelberg - Chemical Institute (Freudenberg, Karl), 1930-1932, 1936-1937, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - University of Konigsberg - Chemistry - (Paneth, Fritz), 1932-1933 (Box 14, Folder 127)
    - University of Konigsberg - Second Physical Institute - (Stuart, Herbert; Equipment), 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 128)
    - University of Leipzig - Chemistry - (Helferich, B.), 1932-1935 (Box 14, Folder 129)
    - University of Leipzig - Chemistry - (Helferich, B.), 1932-1934, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - University of Marburg - Witt, Horst, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - University of Marburg - Zoological Institute - (Schlieper, Carl; Equipment), 1932-1934 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - University of Munich, 1929-1935, 1948-1955 (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - University of Munich, 1929-1935, 1948-1955 (Box 14, Folder 134)
    - University of Munich, 1929-1935, 1948-1955 (Box 14, Folder 135)
    - University of Munich, 1929-1935, 1948-1955 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - University of Munich, 1929-1935, 1948-1955 (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - University of Munich, 1956-1964 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - University of Munich, 1956-1964 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - University of Munich - Reprints, 1952-1957, 1959-1960; 68 items contained in 140, 142 & 143 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - University of Munich - Reprints, 1952-1957, 1959-1960; 68 items contained in 140, 142 & 143 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - University of Munich - Reprints, 1952-1957, 1959-1960; 68 items contained in 140, 142 & 143 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - University of Munich - Reprints, 1952-1957, 1959-1960; 68 items contained in 140, 142 & 143 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - University of Munich - Biology - (Bozler, Emil), 1929-1930 (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - University of Munich - Chemistry, 1931, 1933-1939, 1942, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 145)
    - University of Munich - Chemistry, 1931, 1933-1939, 1942, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 146)
    - University of Munich -Physics - (Sommerfeld, A.), 1930-1932, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 147)
    - University of Tubingen - Mineralogy and Petrology - (Machatschki, F.), 1930 (Box 16, Folder 148)
    - University of Wurzburg - Physical Chemistry - (Ebert, L.), 1930-1932 (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - Germany - Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards, 717.E
    - (Fellowships), 1929-1939 (Box 16, Folder 150)
    - Fellowships Committee, 1930-1938 (Box 16, Folder 151)
    - Notgemeinschaft Der Deutschen Wissenschaft, 1927-1935, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 152)
    - Notgemeinschaft Der Deutschen Wissenschaft, 1927-1935, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 153)
    - Notgemeinschaft Der Deutschen Wissenschaft, 1927-1935, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - Notgemeinschaft Der Deutschen Wissenschaft, 1927-1935, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 155)
  - Germany - Declinations, 717.F
    - Hirschfeld, Erwin - (Refugee, Finance), 1935-1936, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 156)
    - Hirschfeld, Erwin - (Refugee, Finance), 1935-1936, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 157)
  - Germany - Malaria, 717.I
    - (Malaria), 1930-1939 (Box 17, Folder 158)
  - Germany - Humanities and Arts, 717.R
    - Abraham Lincoln Stiftung - Historical Record - Volume I, Volume II, ALS, 1925-1935 (Box 17, Folder 159)
    - Abraham Lincoln Stiftung - Historical Record - Volume I, Volume II, ALS, 1925-1935 (Box 17, Folder 160)
    - Deissmann, Adolf - (Archaeology), 1929, 1932-1937 (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - Institute of International Economics and Maritime Trade, Kiel - Guuch, Wilhelm J. - (Visit, Special Libraries), 1934-1936 (Box 18, Folder 162)
    - Latin Thesaurus, 1931-1939, 1946-1949, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 163)
    - Latin Thesaurus, 1931-1939, 1946-1949, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 164)
    - Latin Thesaurus, 1931-1939, 1946-1949, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 165)
    - Lowith, Karl - (Political Theory, Book Publication), 1935 (Box 18, Folder 166)
    - Orientalistische Literaturzeitung - Historical Record - OL, 1929-1931 (Box 18, Folder 167)
    - Prussian State Library - (Printed Catalog), 1929-1939, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 168)
    - Prussian State Library - (Printed Catalog), 1929-1939, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 169)
    - Prussian State Library - (Printed Catalog), 1929-1939, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 170)
    - Prussian State Library - (Printed Catalog) - Reports, 1928-1937; 15 items contained in 171 and 172 (Box 19, Folder 171)
    - Prussian State Library - (Printed Catalog) - Reports, 1928-1937; 15 items contained in 171 and 172 (Box 19, Folder 172)
    - Radio Personnel - (Columbia University), 1947-1950, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 173)
    - Radio Personnel - (Columbia University), 1947-1950, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 174)
    - University of Bonn - Linguistics - (Menzerath, Paul), 1950-1952 (Box 19, Folder 175)
    - University of Munich - Fiesel, Eva - (Etruscan), 1932-1935 (Box 19, Folder 176)
  - Germany - Social Sciences, 717.S
    - Deutsche Hochschule Fur Politik, Berlin, 1929-1938 (Box 19, Folder 177)
    - Deutsche Hochschule Fur Politik, Berlin, 1929-1938 (Box 19, Folder 178)
    - Deutsche Hochschule Fur Politik, Berlin - Reports, 1932; 5 Items (Box 20, Folder 179)
    - Institute For International Economics and Maritime Trade, Kiel, 1930-1940, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 180)
    - Institute For International Economics and Maritime Trade, Kiel, 1930-1940, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 181)
    - Institute For International Economics and Maritime Trade, Kiel, 1930-1940, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 182)
    - Institute For International Economics and Maritime Trade, Kiel, 1930-1940, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 183)
    - Kaiser Wilhelm Institute, Berlin - International Law, 1929-1932 (Box 20, Folder 184)
    - Kirchhoff, Paul - (Anthropology, Publication), 1932-1935, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 185)
    - KIT-2 Kittredge, Tracy B. "Social Sciences in Germany", 1932; 2 Copies (Box 20, Folder 186)
    - Notgemeinschaft Der Deutschen Wissenschaft - Anthropology, 1929-1935 (Box 20, Folder 187)
    - Notgemeinschaft Der Deutschen Wissenschaft - International Relations, 1931-1934 (Box 20, Folder 188)
    - Raschhofer, Herman - (European Minorities), 1934-1939 (Box 21, Folder 189)
    - Schumacher, H. - (Raw Materials Studies), 1933-1939, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 190)
    - Spiethoff, Arthur - (Business Cycle Research), 1946-1947, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 191)
    - Staehle, Hans H. L. - (Economic Statistics), 1932, 1935, 1939-1940 (Box 21, Folder 192)
    - University of Bonn - Administrative and Economic Sciences, 1931-1938 (Box 21, Folder 193)
    - University of Cologne - Institut Fur Volkerrecht - (Hula, Erich), 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 194)
    - University of Heidelberg - Institute for Social and Political Sciences, 1931, 1934-1937, 1948-1949, 1950-1955 (Box 21, Folder 195)
    - University of Heidelberg - Institute for Social and Political Sciences, 1931, 1934-1937, 1948-1949, 1950-1955 (Box 21, Folder 196)
    - University of Heidelberg - Institute for Social and Political Sciences, 1931, 1934-1937, 1948-1949, 1950-1955 (Box 21, Folder 197)
    - University of Heidelberg - Institute for Social and Political Sciences, 1931, 1934-1937, 1948-1949, 1950-1955 (Box 21, Folder 198)
    - University of Heidelberg - Institute for Social and Political Sciences, 1956-1959 (Box 22, Folder 199)
    - Warburg Institute - (Saxl, Fritz, Refugee), 1933-1937, 1940-1941 (Box 22, Folder 200)
    - Warburg Institute - (Saxl, Fritz, Refugee) - Reports, 1933-1934, 1937-1941; 22 Items (Box 22, Folder 201)
- Greece, 1920-1984; 749; 6 box(es)
  The material is arranged in eight subseries, as follows:
  749 (no program letter; general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  749 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  749 D Natural sciences and agriculture (research usually conducted in departments outside of medical schools, research in pure science, veterinary medicine or agriculture)
  749 I Malaria
  749 J Public health demonstrations, local health units
  749 K Health services (epidemiology, reform, public health administration, laboratories, vital statistics, and particularly sanitary engineering)
  749 L Public health education (schools of hygiene and public health
  749 R Humanities and arts
  - Contracts, 1929-1930, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Health, 1928-1934, 1936-1942, 1944-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Health, 1928-1934, 1936-1942, 1944-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Health, 1928-1934, 1936-1942, 1944-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Institute of Hygiene, Athens, 1929-1930, 1932, 1934-1941, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Institute of Hygiene, Athens, 1929-1930, 1932, 1934-1941, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gregg, Alan - Survey - Medical Education in Greece - GRE, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Greece - Medical Sciences, 749.A
    - Gregg, Alan - Survey - Medical Education in Greece - GRE, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - University of Athens, 1929-1937, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - University of Athens, 1929-1937, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - University of Athens, 1929-1937, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Greece - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 749.D
    - National Technical University, Athens - (Visits; Pippas, Demosthenes; Vassiliou, Philon), 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Greece - Malaria, 749.I
    - (Malaria) - (Appropriations), 1929-1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - (Malaria), 1928-1941, 1943-1948, 1955, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (Malaria), 1928-1941, 1943-1948, 1955, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - (Malaria), 1928-1941, 1943-1948, 1955, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - (Malaria), 1928-1941, 1943-1948, 1955, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - BAL-1 Balfour, Marshall C. and Serdaris, G. S. "Study of Malaria in Region of Rododaphni...", 1930 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - BAR-I - BAR-2 Barber, M. A. and Rice, J. B. "Marlaria Studies in Greece" - Reports, 1932-1933; 2 Items (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - BAR-3 - BAR-5 Barber, M. A. and Rice, J. B. "Marlaria Studies in Greece" - Reports, 1933-1935; 3 Items (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - MEA-1 Mead, Pauline A. "Statistical Analysis of Malaria Field Studies, Through 1938" (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - PUT-1 Putnam, Persis and Mead, Puline A. 'Greece: The Trend of Malaria Observed in Field Studies", 1936 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - WHI-I White, Roland Senior "Notes on Malaria Work of the RF in Southeast Europe", 1934 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Greece - Public Health Demonstrations, 749.J
    - Ambelokipi - (Health Center), 1932-1940, 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Ambelokipi - (Health Center), 1932-1940, 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Greece - Health Services, 749.K
    - Ambelokipi - (Health Center), 1929-1936, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Greece - Public Health Education, 749.L
    - Copanaris, PH. - (Visit, Hygiene), 1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Greece - Humanities and Arts, 749.R
    - American School of Classical Studies - "Record of Declination of Requests for Aid" - Historical Record - ASCS, 1920, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Agora Excavations - "Record of Declination of Request for Aid" - Historical Record - ASCS AE, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Agora Museum, 1937-1941 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Agora Museum, 1942-1945, 1947-1951, 1953-1957, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Agora Museum, 1942-1945, 1947-1951, 1953-1957, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Agora Museum, 1942-1945, 1947-1951, 1953-1957, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Capps Testimonial, 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - American School of Classical Studies -Eleusis Excavations - Historical Record - ASCS EE, 1929-1930, 1932-1937 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships, 1929-1941 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships, 1929-1941 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships, 1942-1947, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships - Annual Reports, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships - Informal Reports, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships - Weekly Reports, 1934-1939 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships - Weekly Reports, 1934-1939 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships - Weekly Reports, 1934-1939 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships - Weekly Reports, 1934-1939 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Fellowships - Weekly Reports, 1934-1939 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Lebos Museum - Historical Record - ASCS LM, 1931-1934 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Theseum, 1939-1940, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Theseum, 1939-1940, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Threpsiades, Johannis - (Epigraphy), 1938-1940 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Wilhelm, Adolph - (Epigraphical Studies) - Historical Record - WIL, 1930, 1933-1935 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Hungary, 1922-1956; 750; 2 Cubic Feet; 5 __Boxes __2 cubic feet
  The records on Hungary document Foundation activity that almost exclusively related to medicine and public health. The University of Budapest received an extensive number of grants in such fields as pediatric medicine, phamacology, physiology and nursing. There is a file covering the work in biochemistry of Albert Szent-Gyorgyi, 1937 winner of the Nobel Prize in medicine and physiology. In the field of public health, the Foundation helped set up local health department in Godollo, Mezokovesd, Pecs, and Vac. There is also a grant, which ran from 1927 through 1931, to the State Hygienic Institute for a study on influenza.
  750 (no program letter; general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  750 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  750 C Nursing (nursing education, public health nursing)